<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>DevOps Today Blog</title>
        <link>https://robwittman.github.io/blog/blog</link>
        <description>DevOps Today Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:37:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unleashing the Power of DevOps Technologies]]></title>
            <link>https://robwittman.github.io/blog/blog/intro</link>
            <guid>https://robwittman.github.io/blog/blog/intro</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:37:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Introduction]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h2><p>Greetings, DevOps enthusiasts, software engineers, and technology aficionados! Welcome to DevopsToday, your ultimate destination for all things DevOps. Here, we embark on an exciting journey through the realms of DevOps technologies, exploring the latest tools, methodologies, and best practices that revolutionize software development and operations.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="about-devopstoday">About DevopsToday<a href="#about-devopstoday" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to About DevopsToday" title="Direct link to About DevopsToday">​</a></h2><p>DevopsToday is not just another tech blog; it's a vibrant community dedicated to demystifying DevOps concepts and empowering individuals to thrive in the ever-evolving world of software engineering. Whether you're a seasoned DevOps practitioner, an aspiring developer, or simply curious about this transformative field, DevopsToday is your go-to resource for deepening your understanding and sharpening your skills.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-mission">Our Mission<a href="#our-mission" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our Mission" title="Direct link to Our Mission">​</a></h2><p>At DevopsToday, our mission is to bridge the gap between developers and operations teams, fostering collaboration and innovation. We firmly believe that embracing DevOps principles and technologies is crucial for delivering high-quality software, streamlining workflows, and achieving continuous improvement. Through engaging and informative content, we aim to empower our readers with the knowledge they need to unlock the true potential of DevOps.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-expect">What to Expect<a href="#what-to-expect" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What to Expect" title="Direct link to What to Expect">​</a></h2><p>DevOps is a vast and dynamic field, encompassing a wide range of tools, methodologies, and cultural practices. DevopsToday is your compass in this ever-changing landscape, guiding you through the following topics and more:</p><ol><li>Continuous Integration and Delivery (CI/CD): Explore the art of building, testing, and deploying software efficiently using tools like Jenkins, GitLab CI, and Travis CI.</li><li>Configuration Management: Dive into the world of infrastructure as code (IaC) using tools like Ansible, Puppet, and Chef to automate and manage your infrastructure.</li><li>Containerization and Orchestration: Discover the power of containerization with Docker and container orchestration platforms like Kubernetes, enabling scalability, portability, and streamlined deployments.</li><li>Cloud Computing and DevOps: Uncover the synergies between cloud platforms such as AWS, Azure, and GCP, and DevOps practices, including infrastructure provisioning, auto-scaling, and serverless computing.</li><li>Monitoring and Observability: Learn about tools like Prometheus, Grafana, and ELK Stack to gain insights into system performance, detect anomalies, and ensure optimal operational efficiency.</li><li>DevSecOps: Explore the integration of security practices throughout the software development lifecycle, from secure coding to vulnerability scanning and threat modeling.</li><li>Collaboration and Culture: Delve into the importance of fostering a collaborative culture, breaking down silos, and embracing cross-functional teams for successful DevOps implementations.</li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="join-the-conversation">Join the Conversation<a href="#join-the-conversation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Join the Conversation" title="Direct link to Join the Conversation">​</a></h2><p>DevopsToday is not just a repository of knowledge; it's a community-driven platform. We encourage you to actively participate, share your experiences, ask questions, and engage in meaningful discussions. Together, we can foster a vibrant exchange of ideas, insights, and practical advice, driving the evolution of DevOps practices.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2><p>Welcome to DevopsToday, where we unravel the power of DevOps technologies with passion, clarity, and a commitment to excellence. We're excited to have you on this journey. Get ready to be inspired, informed, and empowered as we delve into the world of DevOps, enabling you to optimize your software delivery pipelines, enhance collaboration, and propel innovation.</p><p>Stay curious, stay innovative, and let's unlock the true potential of DevOps together!</p><ul><li>The DevopsToday Team</li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Orthus]]></title>
            <link>https://robwittman.github.io/blog/blog/orthus/intro</link>
            <guid>https://robwittman.github.io/blog/blog/orthus/intro</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:37:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Introduction]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h2><p>In today's fast-paced digital landscape, deploying software in the cloud has become a critical aspect of modern business operations. However, this process can be complex and time-consuming, requiring deep knowledge of cloud providers' APIs and infrastructure management. That's where Orthus comes into play. Welcome to our blog post, where we introduce Orthus, an innovative application that automates the deployment of software inside a customer's cloud provider, powered by Crossplane.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="understanding-orthus">Understanding Orthus<a href="#understanding-orthus" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Understanding Orthus" title="Direct link to Understanding Orthus">​</a></h2><p>Orthus is a powerful solution designed to streamline and simplify the process of deploying software in the cloud. It acts as a bridge between the customer's cloud provider and their desired software stack, providing a seamless experience for automating infrastructure provisioning, configuration, and application deployment.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="powered-by-crossplane">Powered by Crossplane<a href="#powered-by-crossplane" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Powered by Crossplane" title="Direct link to Powered by Crossplane">​</a></h2><p>At the core of Orthus lies Crossplane, an open-source multicloud control plane. Crossplane abstracts the underlying infrastructure and allows Orthus to interact with various cloud providers in a consistent manner. By leveraging Crossplane's capabilities, Orthus enables customers to manage their cloud resources efficiently and ensures a consistent experience across different cloud platforms.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="key-features-and-benefits-of-orthus">Key Features and Benefits of Orthus<a href="#key-features-and-benefits-of-orthus" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Key Features and Benefits of Orthus" title="Direct link to Key Features and Benefits of Orthus">​</a></h2><ol><li><p>Automated Deployment: Orthus eliminates the manual effort involved in deploying software by automating infrastructure provisioning and application deployment. With a few simple steps, users can define their desired software stack and let Orthus handle the rest.</p></li><li><p>Multicloud Support: Orthus, powered by Crossplane, supports multiple cloud providers, enabling customers to deploy their software seamlessly across different platforms. This flexibility allows businesses to leverage the best features of each cloud provider without being locked into a single vendor.</p></li><li><p>Infrastructure as Code (IaC): Orthus embraces the Infrastructure as Code paradigm, allowing users to define their desired infrastructure using declarative code. This approach brings repeatability, version control, and easier collaboration to the deployment process.</p></li><li><p>Resource Management: Orthus provides a centralized interface for managing cloud resources, making it simple to create, modify, and delete infrastructure components as needed. This streamlines the management of cloud resources and ensures consistency across deployments.</p></li><li><p>Extensibility and Customization: Orthus offers extensibility through plugins and integrations, allowing users to incorporate additional functionality and customize deployments to suit their specific requirements. This flexibility empowers businesses to tailor Orthus to their unique needs and workflows.</p></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="getting-started-with-orthus">Getting Started with Orthus<a href="#getting-started-with-orthus" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Getting Started with Orthus" title="Direct link to Getting Started with Orthus">​</a></h2><p>To get started with Orthus, users can follow the comprehensive documentation and guides provided by the Orthus team. The documentation covers everything from the initial setup to advanced deployment scenarios, empowering users to make the most of Orthus and Crossplane's capabilities.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2><p>Orthus revolutionizes the way software is deployed in the cloud by automating the process and simplifying infrastructure management. Powered by Crossplane, Orthus provides a seamless and consistent experience across multiple cloud providers, enabling businesses to deploy their software with ease and efficiency. Embracing Infrastructure as Code and offering extensibility, Orthus empowers users to customize their deployments and optimize their cloud infrastructure.</p><p>Explore Orthus today and experience the power of automated cloud software deployment. Say goodbye to manual processes and hello to streamlined, efficient, and scalable deployments with Orthus.</p><ul><li>The Orthus Team</li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>